A Guide to the Matthew Fontaine Maury Papers, 1833-1873
Virginia Military Institute Archives
- Correspondence, Family 1840-1872
  - Letter 1869 February 16 (Box-folder 2/32)
    Place: Richmond, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. References to Corbin's business plans.
  - Letter 1869 April 20 (Box-folder 2/33)
    Place: Richmond, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Note regarding Corbin's business activities.
  - Letter 1869 April 30 (Box-folder 2/34)
    Place: Richmond, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding Corbin's business activities; possibility of trading with Holland.
  - Letter 1869 May 22 (Box-folder 2/35)
    Place: Richmond, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding the acquistion of household goods for move to Lexington (piano, carpets).
  - Letter 1869 June 17 (Box-folder 2/36)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding move of household to Lexington, furnishings, etc. Maury has been offered Presidency of University of Alabama, which he is considering.
  - Letter 1869 September 1 (Box-folder 2/37)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Note regarding bills for household goods.
  - Letter 1869 September 9 (Box-folder 2/38)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding carpets for home in Lexington.
  - Letter 1869 September 10 (Box-folder 2/39)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding 6 dozen napkins for home in Lexington.
  - Letter 1869 September 16 (Box-folder 2/40)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Napkins received; waiting for new cook; children well.
  - Letter 1869 December 20 (Box-folder 2/41)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding Corbin's business prospects.
  - Letter 1870 June 21 (Box-folder 2/42)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Corbin to enter insurance business; discussion of potential for plantations in San Domingo.
  - Letter 1870 March 4 (Box-folder 2/43)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Maury is sending money.
  - Letter 1871 April 6 (Box-folder 2/44)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding Corbin's financial matters.
  - Letter 1871 July 26 (Box-folder 2/45)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to daughter Nannie. Regarding the situation at the University of Alabama and whether or not he will take the position there.
  - Letter 1871 August 9 (Box-folder 2/46)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Family news; reference to University of Alabama position.
  - Letter 1871 August 17 (Box-folder 2/47)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. References to to University of Alabama position and business matters.
  - Letter 1871 September 23 (Box-folder 2/48)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding travel plans; misc. family matters.
  - Letter 1871 November 11 (Box-folder 2/49)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to daughter Nannie. Family news.
  - Letter 1871 December 20 (Box-folder 2/50)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to grandson John Maury Corbin. Family news.
  - Letter 1872 March 1 (Box-folder 2/51)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Family news.
  - Letter 1872 March 27 (Box-folder 2/52)
  - Letter 1872 April 10 (Box-folder 2/53)
  - Letter 1872 April 19 (Box-folder 2/54)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Family news; wants to leave Lexington and settle in eastern Virginia; inquires about a house.
  - Letter 1872 May 10 (Box-folder 2/55)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Family news; mentions search for an affordable house.
  - Letter 1872 May 12 (Box-folder 2/56)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Is traveling to St. Louis; hopes to get out of Lexington by fall.
  - Letter 1872 May 19 (Box-folder 2/57)
    Place: VMI, Lexington, Virginia. MFM to Nannie and Wellford Corbin. Family news; still considering plans to leave Lexington.
  - Letter 1872 May 30 (Box-folder 2/58)
    Place: St. Louis, Missouri. MFM to wife Ann. Regarding his speech, and travel plans.
  - Letter 1872 June 1 (Box-folder 2/59)
    Place: St. Charles County, Missouri. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding his travel plans.
  - Letter 1872 June 19 (Box-folder 2/60)
  - Letter 1872 July 24 (Box-folder 2/61)
  - Letter 1872 August 11 (Box-folder 2/62)
    Place: Knoxville, Tennessee. MFM to wife, Ann. Regarding his trip and travel plans.
  - Letter 1872 September 4 (Box-folder 2/63)
    Place: Knoxville, Tennessee. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Regarding financial matters.
  - Letter 1872 September 8 (Box-folder 2/63)
  - Letter 1872 September 15 (Box-folder 2/64)
    Place: New York (Jim's). MFM to wife Ann. News of trip, including note by Eliza Maury.
  - Letter 1872 October 10 (Box-folder 2/65)
    Place: St. Louis, Missouri. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Is ill and cannot continue journey home.
  - Telegram 1872 October 17 (Box-folder 2/66)
    Place: St. Louis, Missouri. MFM to Wellford Corbin. Expect us by train tonight.
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous Business and Personal, 1833-1873 (Box-folder 3/1-20)
- Printed materials, 1852-1873 (Box 4)